Previously on Smallville.
I knew you would return, my son.
It felt as though something was calling me home.
Everything we've been through with Jor-El, I just wanted to close that chapter in my life.
There's a darkness in me that I can't always control.
Well, you certainly see me at my worst.
And at your best.
Three relics hidden around the world by scientifically advanced ancient cultures.
That one means fire and the one up there, that's air.
Put them together.
Where is it?
God help me.
By now you'd know that Lana's nothing more than my mother's pawn.
Martha, Clark still feels responsible for my heart problems.
If you found out something, something someone didn't want you to know about them, would you tell them?
What'd I do?
You trusted me.
I can't let you walk out, not again.
That's why this time will be different.
This time?
You're an amazing young man, Clark.
You make life and death decisions every day.
Trust your gut.
Greed will drive others to hunt the stones.
And will drive the world to famine, war, and the Earth's ultimate destruction.
Where is the stone?
I gave it to Lana.
Well, she is the chosen one and we all know that.
Clark's more connected to this than any of us.
It's Clark.
He's the man who can't deny his true nature.
It is time to fulfill my destiny.
Clark.
I am the villain of the story.
And now, the season finale of Smallville.
I have to applaud you, Lana.
I raised my son to have a willpower that couldn't be broken by anything.
Except for you.
I'm sorry.
Except his love for you, apparently.
What do you want from me?
The stone.
The one Lionel gave you.
Lionel?
He never gave me any.
I'm going to find it whether you help me or not.
I'm sorry.
Ah, buddy, let's leave it at that.
No, don't be.
Nothing, son.
I appreciate it so much.
What's gonna happen to me?
I'm gonna go to prison.
No.
I've retained one of the best defense attorneys in the country.
And once he arrives from New York, we'll go to the authorities.
Okay. Thank you.
Now, you have to trust me.
Until the lawyer arrives, I want you to stay here and talk to no one.
My purse. Where's my purse?
Don't worry. It's still there.
I'd never take it from you.
Mr. Luther, we have a situation.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm sorry.
I can't help but feel this is some kind of warning.
Clark, it was nothing but a bad dream.
You used to have nightmares all the time when you were little, remember?
This time's different.
It felt so real.
And if it is a warning, I need to do something.
Yeah, what you need to do is you need to get some shut-eye
so that you're not half asleep tomorrow when they hand you that diploma.
Your dad's right.
Don't let a nightmare spoil your high school graduation.
Nightmare?
So that's what all this commotion is about.
Lois.
You know, if it makes you feel any better, I have them all the time.
I had this one last week.
Really scary.
It was this, uh...
gun.
Guy wearing a red cape.
Wow, that sounds horrible, Lois.
Yeah.
There's something I wanted to tell all you guys.
I just didn't know when to, so I guess two in the morning's as good a time as any.
What is it, Lois?
Oh, the generals recruited me on a recon mission
to track down my sister, the grifter, in Europe.
So we're headed for Heidelberg tomorrow.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Clark, I know how devastated you must be,
but if you could just keep your tears to a minimum, I'd appreciate it.
I'll try.
Thanks.
Mr. and Mrs. Kent, I just wanted to say thanks for everything.
You guys are like the mom and dad I've always wanted to have.
Lois, we want you to know that you are welcome back here any time.
Actually...
We'll all miss you, Lois.
I'll miss you all, too.
Him?
Not so much.
I thought I'd do Miss Lange a favor and tidy up the place a bit.
I'll miss you, too.
She left it quite a mess.
Quite a mess.
What are you looking for, Dad?
A good housekeeping seal of approval?
You know, for a woman without a heart,
Genevieve Teague certainly did have a lot of blood.
You didn't come here to do a post-mortem on Genevieve Teague.
What is it you want?
I'd like to offer a trade.
Lana Lang's freedom.
In exchange for the, um, artifact she has in her possession.
Dad, don't you think your search for these three ancient stones
is starting to border on the fanatical?
Let me remind you, Langs.
It was you who looted the ruins of Egypt.
To get your hands on one of those stones.
Trust me, Lana Lang has nothing to do with this.
Oh, it's so chivalrous of you.
You were the gallant hero trying to protect the damsel in distress.
Hmm?
I'm warning you.
Leave her alone.
All your life, you've had a tendency to let the damsel
lead you straight into the mouth of the dragon.
Your feelings for Miss Lang, don't let them cripple your common sense, son.
I expect to see that stone by noon tomorrow.
It would be a shame if Genevieve's corpse were delivered to the sheriff
with Lana Lang's DNA as postage.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sir, you better take a look at the right ascension.
How long has there been activity?
There was nothing there ten seconds ago.
It just came out of nowhere.
Oh, my God.
It's headed straight for Earth.
I realize hand-eye coordination isn't one of your strong suits,
but I'm sure you've had a lot of fun.
Here.
Let me help you with that.
Lois, I'm not sure what I'm gonna do without you.
Oh, come on, Clark.
Your future's laid out right in front of you.
You're gonna go to community college, major in agriculture,
probably minor in law enforcement,
and then you and Lana are gonna have a nice little church wedding.
Excuse me?
It's written in the stars, and you know it.
It's only a matter of time before you join the bowling league,
take over the family farm, and then, well,
you and Lana can bring little Clark Junior into the world.
I think you're hallucinating.
No.
Hallucinating would be imagining Clark Kent going off to the big city
to make his mark in the world.
I'm just being realistic.
Oh.
Well, Lois, what are your big plans after Europe?
You gonna go back to school?
Maybe actually stay a little while?
I have a feeling that if I'm gonna get an education,
it's gonna be in the real world.
You know, I took this career test in some magazine.
It said that my perfect job would be a radio station.
I'm not sure.
I'm gonna be a radio disc jockey.
That makes sense.
You talk enough, there won't be any dead air.
You mock me now, Smallville, but you just wait and see.
Journalism.
You ever thought about that?
You wrote some half-decent articles
at your short-lived career at the Torch.
Aw, kill me first.
Even if I could spell, the last thing I'd want to do
is spend my time in a newsroom.
With my luck, I'd probably end up across the desk
from the most bumbling reporter on the masthead.
You know what?
You actually look handsome for a change.
I'll take that as a compliment.
Look, I know we've had our disagreements in the past,
and I will be the first to admit
that I've made it my own little hobby to bust your chops.
I'm used to it.
Besides, I know I haven't been the most gracious host.
Look, I just want you to know, Clark,
that when I'm sitting in the audience today at your graduation
and you stand up on that stage and run about all those people,
I'm gonna be looking up at you and thinking one thing.
What's that?
Please, God, don't let him trip.
See ya.
Darren Cooper.
Caroline Drees.
Cody Davis.
Erica Felder.
You seen Lana yet?
Still no sign.
I'm starting to get worried.
Lana's never so much as had a tardy.
She's not gonna miss her high school graduation.
She'll be here.
Max Schultz.
Michael Hall.
Holly Harrell.
Fabienne Barry.
Tamia Hart.
Kate Hartman.
Michael Hoover.
Hannah Jacobs.
Michelle Jewel.
Oh, there's Clark.
Clark Kent.
San Clark!
Lana Lang.
Attention. Remain calm.
Over.
By order of the Federal Emergency Decree,
all non-essential personnel must evacuate the area
within a 50-mile radius.
In approximately three hours,
a meteor shower is predicted to hit Slowville.
Ladies and gentlemen, please, please,
open the passageway.
Oh, my God.
Man, wait till you're parked.
Not again.
Please, remain calm.
No need to panic.
Please, senior, park.
Please, ask.
Hey, Clark, can you believe it?
Twice in 16 years.
I mean, this is the first time
I've seen a meteor shower.
This is crazy.
Smallville's got to have
some sort of extraterrestrial bull's eye on it.
It's pretty weird, huh?
Well, there's got to be
some kind of connection in the cosmos.
I mean, this is not just a coincidence.
Yeah, I'm sure there's some sort of explanation.
Well, there's just something in Smallville
that is screaming for celestial attention.
I mean, lightning does not strike twice in the same place
without some kind of lightning rod, right?
I just wonder what that is.
I'm not sure, but we don't have much time.
We need to find Lana.
You're right, and if anyone can find her
with moments to spare, it's equal.
Why do you say that?
I don't know, because you have a way
of getting things done,
and half the time,
a normal person gets things done.
And I'm not normal?
No, of course you're normal, Clark.
You're as normal as they come.
Now let's hurry and find Lana.
Look, I'm sure she's already out of town.
They've evacuated half of the county.
They probably saw her running in late
and told her to leave town.
Well, it's exactly what you two
need to do right now.
Thanks for the tip.
Now listen to me, Smallville.
If there's one thing that the general has taught me,
he's taught me that you cannot panic in times of crisis.
Do you hear me?
Okay, whatever happens, you have to stay calm.
You cannot panic, because if you lose your mind,
you cannot panic, because if you lose your cool,
then you can do what?
Lois, you're panicking.
Fine.
Clark, where the hell have you been?
We gotta pack up.
I've been looking for Lana everywhere.
I can't find her.
Sweetheart, she's probably already been evacuated.
I want you to go up to your room
and pack everything that's necessary.
Your mom and I will take care of everything down here.
No, I gotta do something first.
Don't think for a second this is your fault.
I came to Smallville in a meteor shower.
Now it's happening again, and it's all because of me.
Clark, there is absolutely nothing you could have done
to prevent this.
We don't know that.
There's gotta be something I can do.
Clark, you don't have time.
I don't have a choice.
I'm sorry.
Lex, what are you doing here?
I didn't know the forecasting Gurley from the newspaper
was Everything Everything.
Nobody everywhere.
Neither in a world it wasieneither?
Maybe you don't know?
I wanted to offer you and your parents safe passage out of here in a lithocorp jet.
The roads are gonna get pretty ugly soon.
Thanks, but I think we'll be okay.
Clark, why take the risk?
The first meteor shower caused me irrevocable damage.
Trust me, you don't want to be anywhere near here when the next one hits.
Thanks, Lex, but I think my dad's gonna want to pack up the truck with as much as we can take.
I understand.
Something simply can't be replaced.
Clark, my scientists have identified what seems to be an inner chamber inside the cave wall.
Really?
I was wondering if your research into the cave might have turned up anything similar.
No, but Lex, why are you so interested in the caves when there's a natural disaster headed our way?
Clark, if anything in this town is irreplaceable, it's those caves.
They've been around for thousands of years,
and they could very well be destroyed.
Well, let's hope they're not.
I really need to get to helping my parents.
Good luck, Lex.
Thanks, Clark, but I don't believe in luck.
It's our wits and our fortitude to keep us safe.
And I'm sure you have more than enough of both.
Stay safe.
You're my father.
Talk to me.
Tell me what you've done.
It was you who brought this upon yourself, Carlisle.
What did I do?
I sent you here to unite the three elements.
The stones?
They have nothing to do with me!
But they do, Carlisle.
For the knowledge of the universe is meant for you only.
Yet you chose to deny your heritage.
Today, you will witness the consequences.
Did you send a meteor shower?
I have done nothing, Carlisle.
Human blood has stained one of the elements
and awakened a great danger from the darkness of space.
What can I do to stop it?
There is nothing you can do to prevent what is already in motion.
But the meteor shower is just beginning, Carlisle.
I warned you that the elements could not fall into the hands of a human.
The three must become one.
It is the only way to save Earth from total annihilation.
I don't know where they are!
I don't have time to find them!
If you don't unite them at once,
you, my son, will be seared by a fire from the sky.
Even you can't survive.
The future of mankind rests in your hands, Carlisle.
Please! Help me! I can't do this alone!
I can't believe I almost forgot this!
That's great, sweetheart. I almost have the truck all loaded up.
Great!
Show me the load up!
Clark.
Great.
Would you help me secure the truck?
You're gonna have to go without me.
What?
Do I have to remind you, Clark,
that the last time we had a meteor shower was full of kryptonite?
If the same thing happens today, it could kill you.
You have to come with us.
I spoke to Jor-El.
No.
He told me I have to find the other two stones right now
and unite it with the one in the cave.
No!
You're my son!
You're not gonna go on some kind of suicide mission!
Clark, you might be stronger than steel,
but you're not invincible.
I know, Dad.
But I'm the only one who can do this.
I'm the only one who can do this.
I know, Dad.
All right?
I want you to listen to me right now.
All the years that your mother and I spent raising you
from a wide-eyed toddler running around on this farm
to the man who is standing in front of me right now
was for this moment.
You do this, son.
You make us proud.
Come on, Clark.
Come on.
All right?
Go ahead.
You do this, son.
You make us proud.
Give him back the exactly what he owes ­all of us.
Tell that with his own eyes what he owes.
You !!
This is what you offered me, manого.
Give me a hug.
What are you talking about?
Those meteors can't kill him, Jonathan.
I know that, sweetheart.
But if we have faith in our son,
then we can't let that faith waver now.
No.
Lana, I thought you already evacuated.
Are you okay?
I'm scared.
Lana, I know this meteor shower
must bring up some painful memories for you.
But this time is different.
We have warning and we'll be safe.
No, I'm not so sure.
Clark, I don't know what's going to happen to me.
I want you to have faith in me.
I don't want to live this.
Where'd you get this?
In China.
Whatever it is, whatever it means,
I...
I somehow know that it's meant for you.
Is this blood?
Remember all those times
that I asked you for an explanation
but you said you couldn't give me one?
That I had to trust you?
Well, this time I need you to trust me.
Lana, my parents are about to leave right now.
Go with them. You'll be safe.
I can't.
You have to.
Maybe I'll find some place to live
with my brother.
I's probably better
if you find a good place to live.
And this timeeto make it up for thisóc
What?
I want to leave the feeling
of being so near to you again.
You never questioned my feelings.
You know?
I'm afraid I probably mean it.
But there's no way
the Bamboo Boys can be friends now.
I can never forgive my love for you.
I know.
There's some tiene
that I need to get asap.
Clark, I need you to know
that whatever happen
I'll never forget you.
.
I love you too.
Goodbye.
Chloe, even though you won't hear from me for a while, I want you to know that I'm
okay.
I thought we agreed you wouldn't talk to anyone.
I have to let my friends know that I'm all right.
Lana, I understand you not wanting them to worry, but you have to trust me.
Now, I assume the stone is still safe?
As safe as can be.
Let's keep it that way.
I'll put it in my vault.
Why?
A chopper is being fueled to evacuate you to Metropolis, where you'll stay at a hotel
until your lawyer arrives.
It's probably best not to travel with the murder weapon.
I understand that, Lex, but I'd rather hold onto it.
Lana, that object is what prosecutors fondly refer to as the smoking gun.
Now, I'll do anything I can to protect you, including supporting whatever story of self-defense
you want to run with.
I'm sorry.
I was not even shut down.
Your brother there will still teach you the whole tinkering that I have with a wanna…
I'm sorry, Lex.
I'm sorry, Norm.
As I've originally done, the person I face now never compromise.
Because I don't leave my name.
That's not my kind of truth.
Act so you can have your do, end your life.
Hey…
Jason?
Jason!
No!
Shelby, no.
I'm having what you can call a rough day.
Why don't you just calm down, son?
Where's Clark?
He's not here.
Why don't you put down the shotgun and we'll talk about it.
Tell me where he is!
He's in trouble, Lois.
I can't abandon her.
I mean, the mansion's just right around that bend.
Unless you have a jetpack in your purse.
We're not going anywhere.
Stop!
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We're purchasing vehicles only.
Turn the car around and exit the impact zone immediately.
Well, our friend could be trapped inside.
We're just gonna go grab her and then come right back.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
No one gets through.
We're way too close to turn away.
Hey, soldier!
Is this a roadblock or a lemonade stand you got here?
Wait a second.
I recognize you.
You're the...
Daughter of General Lane?
You might have heard of him.
He talks real loud, smokes a stogie.
Hey!
This barricade?
It should be perpendicular to the road.
Those channelizers should be further apart.
And unless I need glasses,
there should be reflectors on those eye beams.
Yes, ma'am, I understand.
But I can't let you through.
You're a cubs' got-out-here soldier.
Where's your dead mother?
Baking brownies?
Oh!
What happened to your survival instincts, Dad?
Fire and brimstone are about to rain down from the sky,
and you're sipping a cocktail like it's Sunday at the country club.
I am aware of the imminent danger, Lex,
but I'm not about to leave without knowing that my son is all right.
Come on, who's kidding who?
You're not about to leave without the element.
I hate to disappoint you, but I haven't even seen Lana Lang.
She's probably on the run halfway to Costa Rica by now.
A face like Lana Lang's isn't easy to hide.
It's just a matter of time before she catches the attention of some customs official.
All right.
Agree to leave her alone,
and I'll give you something you desperately need.
I am a blessed man, Lex. I need very little in life.
I wonder.
What good is a key if you don't know where the lock,
is?
Wise observation.
Why do you think any of this applies to me?
You have one of the elements, Dad. That much is clear.
What you don't have is the knowledge of where it belongs.
I can help you.
Take you there right now.
I wish it were true, Lex, but I don't have the stone.
No.
Mr. Luther, what happened?
Get J.D. and take my father upstairs.
Mr. Luther, we're evacuating.
Do it!
Can you hear me, Dad?
Before you leave this earth, I want you to know
you did create the son you always wanted.
You did create the son you always wanted.
Come on, hurry up.
Jason, why don't you let Martha go?
She doesn't know anything about any of this.
Oh, a mother always knows her son's deep, dark secrets.
Now, where does he keep the stones?
Why would Clark know anything about ancient stones?
All right, that's good.
Well, let's see.
When I ran into your son in Shanghai,
I decided to do a little homework on my own.
The more I learned about the stone, the more I learned about the stone.
The more I dug, the more Clark Kent's name just got popping up.
Sit down!
Was that a coincidence that the symbols were burned in the ore field?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Jason!
What about Clark's connection to Rizit Crosby?
I don't know.
She had one of the artifacts.
I suppose that was just a coincidence, too.
None of that makes any difference now.
You know, when my mother came to Smallville,
she thought the Luthers would lead her to the stones.
She was wrong.
He was a farm boy.
The one who has no record of ever being born.
He's more connected to those stones than any of us.
There is a meteor shower about to tear this town apart.
You need to get to your mother and get her to safety.
Don't you think I know that?
I can't find her anywhere!
But I'll tell you one thing.
When I do find my mother,
I'll finally be able to give her the one thing she's been searching for all these years.
Now tell me where the stones are!
I'll meet you in Metropolis!
What, you're not coming?
I have a pressing matter to take care of.
Now Lana, for your own safety,
I need that stone.
Look, we all have a need to cling on to things,
but eventually you have to loosen your grip.
It's too dangerous for you.
I don't have it!
Lies don't become you.
It's the truth, Lex. I don't have it.
Trust me, it's safe. I promise.
Where is it?
This was never about my safety, was it?
This was about you getting your hands on that stone!
Lana...
Your safety is more important than any of this!
It means a lot more to me than you know.
Can't wait any longer, Mr. Luthor! We gotta go!
The last stone in the world...
...was found in the first place.
Lana...
Lana?
Oh, my God, Clark.
Clark.
Oh, my God.
Lex, I was looking for Lana.
She's already left.
What happened?
I don't know. I just walked in.
You know more than you're telling me, Chloe.
Who did this?
Lex, honestly, I just came to find Lana.
Your curiosity seems to always have a way of landing you in precarious positions.
Only this time, you're out on a very narrow ledge with only one way back.
Now, who took the element?
Lex, I swear I don't know what you're talking about.
But I think we need to get out of Smallville before the meteor shower hits.
We're gonna find that stone, Chloe,
even if that means dodging a few meteors in the process.
You're coming with me.
I don't...
Let's go.
Lex, don't go.
It's fine.
I swear to God, if you don't start talking, I'm gonna blow her brains out.
Sweetheart, it's no good.
Go ahead, tell him what he wants to know.
Tell him where the stones are.
What?
Do what I want to know.
Okay, okay.
Go upstairs.
To Clark's room.
Ah!
I got him!
I'm sorry.
I Am.
I am.
I AM.
I Am.
I tem.
I TEM.
I T umpt.
I O T T E.
S-S-Shit.
S-
I'm sorry.